Shayne Lemons

Salemons66@gmail.com | 360-213-8473

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Dedicated, hard-working, and loyal Manufacturing Professional with over five years of experience operating Kinetic 2500 and K5000 CNC cutting machines. Thorough and efficient worker with an eye for detail and a focus on producing high-quality results. Recognized by colleagues and supervisors for work ethic, willingness to collaborate, and eagerness to learn new skills.

EXPERIENCE

Kinetic Operator | Vigor Industrial (May 2020 to Oct. 2020)

- Operated Kinetic K5000 CNC machines to cut stainless steel and carbon steel to produce finished and unfinish parts to be further machined
- Adjusted speed/feed settings for Kennametal drills for different materials
- Operated overhead crane, including rigging material to be lifted using chains, lifting clamps, and plate hooks
- Cleaned and maintained machines, as well as tools required to run the machine

Kinetic Operator | Columbia Machine, Inc. (Feb. 2015 to May 2020)

- Operated Kinetic 2500 and K5000 CNC machines to drill, mill, tap, countersink, and plasma and flame cut different alloys of carbon steel to produce finished and unfinished parts to be further machined
- Created programs to run on the machines using Kinetics Primecut 3 and Primecut NE nesting software
- Operated overhead crane, including rigging material to be lifted using chains, lifting clamps, and plate hooks
- Loaded material to be cut and unloading parts and scrap using overhead cranes and forklift
- Cleaned and maintained machines, as well as tools required to run the machine

Dishwasher and Busser | Fatty Patty's Restaurant (Sept. 2010 to Feb. 2015)

• Washed and put away dishes, cleared tables, maintained buffet area, assisted other employees as needed, and cleaned personal work area

EDUCATION

• 2010: High School Diploma, Battle Ground High School

REFERENCES

- Brandon Pogue | Columbia Machine, Inc., K5000 Operator | 360-521-3395
- Kelly Cousineau | Portland State University Assistant Director | 503-984-4018, cousin2@pdx.edu